import { SquareRoot, superscript, subscript, BoldText, ItalicText, Fraction, ShortFraction, LongFraction, MixedFraction, Isotopes } from "@/mathnotation"

const path = "@/assets/images/pastquestions-figures/integratedscience/integratedscienceA/integratedscience-"

export const INTEGRATEDSCIENCEA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The component of white light which is most deviated when light is dispersed is",
A: "blue",
B: "red",
C: "violet",
D: "yellow",
answer: "C. violet",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. Which of the following characters in humans of sex-linked",
A: "Baldness",
B: "Skin colour",
C: "Eye colour",
D: "Sickle cell",
answer: "C. Eye colour",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. An example of an abiotic factor in an ecosystem is",
A: "altitude",
B: "grazing",
C: "predation",
D: "shading",
answer: "A. altitude",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Alkanoic acids contain",
A: "carbon atoms and hydrogen atoms only",
B: "carbon atoms, hydrogen atoms only",
C: "carbon atoms, hydrogen atoms and oxygen atoms only",
D: "carbon atoms, hydrogen atoms and nitrogen atoms only",
answer: "C. carbon atoms, hydrogen atoms and oxygen atoms only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Which of the following minerals is not needed by crops in large quantities",
A: "Calcium",
B: "Iron",
C: "Nitrogen",
D: "Photsphorus",
answer: "B. Iron",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. A rigid bar is supported at a point about which turning occurs is",
A: "lever",
B: "pulley",
C: "wheel and axle",
D: "inclined plane",
answer: "A. lever",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. One criterion used in the classification of domestic rabbit is the",
A: "age",
B: "eye colour",
C: "height",
D: "size",
answer: "B. eye colour",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Which of the following chemical substances is toxic",
A: "Potassium cyanide",
B: "Sodium hydroxide",
C: "Hydrogen peroxide",
D: "Calcium oxide",
answer: "A. Potassium cyanide",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. The unit of heredity found in the chromosomes is",
A: "centriole",
B: "deoxyribonucleic acid",
C: "mitochondrion",
D: "endoplasmic reticulum",
answer: "B. deoxyribonucleic acid",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following elements is a constituent of brass",
A: "Iron",
B: "Magnesium",
C: "Tin",
D: "Zinc",
answer: "D. Zinc",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. The process in the hydrological cycle which results in water vapour condensing and falling on the earth surface is",
A: "evaporation",
B: "infiltration",
C: "precipitation",
D: "sublimation",
answer: "C. precipitation",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The centre of gravity of a body is",
A: "always as its centre",
B: "a point where its total mass is always concentrated",
C: "always at its end",
D: "a point where it can be supported to be in equilibrium",
answer: "B. a point where its total mass is always concentrated",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Which of the following crops is a root vegetable",
A: "carrot",
B: "Ginger",
C: "Lettuce",
D: "Onion",
answer: "C. Lettuce",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The aim of the ring experiment in a flowering plant is to demonstrate that",
A: "water is transported by the xylem",
B: "food substances are transported by the phloem",
C: "food substances are formed in the stem",
D: "water is excreted from the stem",
answer: "B. food substances are transported by the phloem",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. Which of the following properties is associated with ionic compound. They",
A: "are soluble in organic solvents",
B: "conduct electricity in the molten state",
D: "consist of molecules",
answer: "B. conduct electricity in the molten state",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The sedimentary rock is also referred to as",
A: "stratified rock",
B: "slated rock",
C: "silica rock",
D: "separated rock",
answer: "A. stratified rock",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. One similarity of arteries and capillaries is that both have",
A: "permeable walls",
B: "muscular walls",
C: "no valves",
D: "large lumens",
answer: "C. no valves",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Which of the following instruments is most suitable for measuring the thickness of razor blade",
A: "Metre rule",
B: "Micrometer screw gauge",
C: "Vernier calipers",
D: "Surveyor’s tape",
answer: "B. Micrometer screw gauge",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. The chemical which is most likely to have highly inflammable hazard symbol on its container is",
A: "ethanol",
B: "mercury",
C: "annomium hydroxide",
D: "sodium hydroxide",
answer: "A. ethanol",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. The part of the maize gain which grows into the shoot is the",
A: "cotyledon",
B: "endosperm",
C: "plumule",
D: "radicle",
answer: "C. plumule",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. An effort of 120 N was used to overcome a load of 80 N. what is the mechanical advantage of the system",
A: "0.67",
B: "1.50",
C: "40.00",
D: "200.00",
answer: "A. 0",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Which of the following reactions can produce salt and water only",
A: "NaOH (aq) + CH3COOH (aq)",
B: "NaOH (aq) + NH3(aq)",
C: "NH3(aq) + H2O (1)",
D: "NaCl(aq) + AgNO3(aq)",
answer: "A. NaOH (aq) – CH3COOH (aq)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. The best way of harvesting hot pepper is by",
A: "shaking the plant",
B: "handpicking the fruits",
C: "allowing the fruits to drop naturally",
D: "cutting the fruit with a sharp knife",
answer: "D. cutting the fruit with sharp knife",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The area occupied by a box placed on a table is 2.0m2. if the box exerts a pressure of 50 Pa on the table, calculate the mass of the box(g=10 ms-2",
A: "2.5 kg",
B: "10.0 kg",
C: "100.0kg",
D: "1000.0 kg",
answer: "B. 10",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. Which of the following substances would have a pH below 7",
A: "pure water",
B: "Milk of magnesia",
C: "Wood ash",
D: "Lemon juice",
answer: "D. Lemon juice",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
instruction: "Consider the food chain below and use it to answer questions 26 to 27 Grass – Earthworm – Frog – Hawk",
id: "question26",
question: "26. Which of the organisms is the primary consumer",
A: "Earthworm",
B: "Frog",
C: "Grass",
D: "Hawk",
answer: "A. Earthworm",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The organism which obtains the least energy is",
A: "earthworm",
B: "frog",
C: "grass",
D: "hawk",
answer: "D. Hawk",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. In cattle, anaemia, damaged skin and heart water disease are cause by",
A: "liver-fluke",
B: "roundworm",
C: "tapeworm",
D: "tick",
answer: "D. tick",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. In a simple machine, the force that overcomes the resistance is",
A: "effort",
B: "lever",
C: "load",
D: "pivot",
answer: "A. effort",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. A molar solutios of KHSO4 contains K= 39, H=1, S=32, O=16)",
A: "80g of KHSO4 in 1 dm3 of solution",
B: "100g of KHSO4 in 100 cm3 of solution",
C: "120 g of KHSO4 in 1000cm3 of solution",
D: "136 g of KHSO4 in 1 dm3 of solution",
answer: "D. 126 g of KHSO4 in 1 dm3 of solution",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. The most appropriate time to transplant vegetable seedlings is",
A: "dawn",
B: "mid-day",
C: "sunrise",
D: "sunset",
answer: "C. I, II and IlI only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. Which of the following functions are associated with mammalian skeleton. It  \nI. stores calcium and phosphate \nII. protects vital internal internal organs \nIII. produces red blood cells \nIV. stores proteins",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "II, III and IV only",
answer: "D. sunset",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Rainbow formation is a practical illustration of the light phenomenon known as",
A: "dispersion",
B: "interference",
C: "mirage",
D: "reflection",
answer: "A. dispersion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. An example of a metalloid is",
A: "magnesium",
B: "potassium",
C: "phosphorus",
D: "silicon",
answer: "D. silicon",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following statements about animals are correct \nI. Movement I quick and visible \nII. Chloroplast is absent \nIII. They have thick cellulose cell wall",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The main reason for trimming the sides of a vegetable bed is to control",
A: "run-off water",
B: "leaching of nutrients",
C: "breaking of bed",
D: "soil erosion",
answer: "A. run-off water",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Which of the following observations is a direct consequence of thermal expansion \nI. Cracks in concrete slabs \nII. Sagging of electric cables \nIII. Buckling in railway lines \nIV. Crackling noise from roofing sheets",
A: "I, II and IV only",
B: "I, III and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, II, III and IV",
answer: "D. I, II, III and IV",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. A solution of volume 500cm3 contains 9.80g of H2SO4. Determine it molar concentration. [S=32,O=16.H=1]",
A: "0.10M",
B: "0.20M",
C: "0.40",
D: "0.50",
answer: "B. 0",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. A ball and socket jointinthe human body does not allow",
A: "circular movement",
B: "side-to-side movement",
C: "up and down movement",
D: "gilding movement",
answer: "D. gliding movement",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. The best way of controlling end parasites in cattle is through",
A: "rotational grazing",
B: "early morning grazing",
C: "dipping the animals",
D: "spraying the animal with the recommended pesticides",
answer: "C. dipping the animals",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. An electrical circuit consist of a 2V cell connected to a5W resistor. Determine the amount of current through the resistor when the circuit is closed",
A: "0.4A",
B: "1.0A",
C: "2.5A",
D: "4.0A",
answer: "A. 0",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Which of the following hydrocarbons is alkyne",
A: "C2H2",
B: "C2H4",
C: "C3H6",
D: "C3H8",
answer: "A. C2H2",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. An example of multicellular organism is",
A: "amoeba",
B: "euglena",
C: "paramecium",
D: "rhizopus",
answer: "D. Rhizopus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. Farmers prefer to grow crops on loamy soils because loamy soils \nI. usually contain large amounts of plant nutrients \nII. protect the crops from injury \nIII. have equal amounts of clay and sand \nIV. hold plants firmly \nWhich of the statements above is/are correct",
A: "I only",
B: "I and II only",
C: "I and III only",
D: "I and IV only",
answer: "A. I only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. A precaution that has to be taken when using a liquid-in-glass thermometer is",
A: "holding the bulb in hand when in use",
B: "taking the reading quickly before thermal equilibrium is attained",
C: "ensuring that the blub is fully immersed in the substance",
D: "ensuring that the blub  touches the vessel containing the substance",
answer: "C. ensuring that the bulb is fully immersed in the substance",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. Soap may itch the skin when it contains  excess",
A: "acid",
B: "alkali",
C: "Fat",
D: "glycerol",
answer: "B. alkali",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The gas  in the  atmosphere that absorbs ulta violet rays is",
A: "carbon (IV) oxide",
B: "nitrogen",
C: "oxygen",
D: "ozone",
answer: "D. ozone",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Asoil is considered fertile when it",
A: "contains a lot of living organisms",
B: "is highly aerated",
C: "has high water retention ability",
D: "can support adequate crop yield",
answer: "D. can support adequate crop yield",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. The energy possessed by a student on top of a building is",
A: "chemical energy",
B: "heat energy",
C: "kinetic energy",
D: "potential energy",
answer: "D. potential energy",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Which of the following statements about water is correct? It turns blue anhydrous cobalt (II)",
A: "green",
B: "red",
C: "white",
D: "yellow",
answer: "B. red",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},



]